<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Data Science Portfolio on Keltings</title>
    <link>https://keltings.github.io/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Data Science Portfolio on Keltings</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 09 Dec 2022 10:58:08 -0400</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://keltings.github.io/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>A Movie Recommender Engine</title>
      <link>https://keltings.github.io/post/project-1/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 09 Dec 2022 10:58:08 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://keltings.github.io/post/project-1/</guid>
      <description>Think about the way Netflix (or youtube) recommends which movies you should watch next based on what you’ve seen up to this point. It is able to use your previous viewing experiences as a guide to put you into a “group” of Netflix viewers. Based on that information it can infer future viewing patterns simply using enough data of this type.
Recommender systems are the unsung heroes of our modern technological world.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Artist Booking Site</title>
      <link>https://keltings.github.io/post/project-5/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 13 Nov 2022 11:15:58 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://keltings.github.io/post/project-5/</guid>
      <description>This is a site that facilitates bookings between artists who can play at venues, and venues who want to book artists.
It is a web application build to create, read, update and delete(CRUD) operations on a database. These operations are applied across both databases and web applications. Important principles and patterns in building data models for the web and setting up relationships between elements were implemented The web app connected successfully to a PostgreSQL database.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Faulty Air Quality Sensor Hackathon</title>
      <link>https://keltings.github.io/post/project-4/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 14 Oct 2022 11:25:05 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://keltings.github.io/post/project-4/</guid>
      <description>Device failure detection and monitoring is critical to AirQo’s business; faulty devices need to be identified, isolated and fixed or replaced with urgency. Data received from a device can be used to identify whether the device is working correctly or not.
As a participator in the 2022 Umoja Hackathon, I collaborated in the Faulty Air Quality Sensor Challenge. The model we built was used to classify if a sensor is faulty or not.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Coffee Shop Full Stack</title>
      <link>https://keltings.github.io/post/project-7/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 12 Oct 2022 11:14:48 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://keltings.github.io/post/project-7/</guid>
      <description>A new digitally enabled coffee shop where students can order drinks, socialize, and study was recently opened. But the company needed help setting up their menu experience.
I Build the backend for this coffee shop app, implemented adding of user accounts and authenitcation to the application and used role-based access management strategies to control different types of user behaviour in the site.Furthermore, it able to design against key security principals and securing a REST API.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Trivia App</title>
      <link>https://keltings.github.io/post/project-6/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 12 Sep 2022 11:14:48 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://keltings.github.io/post/project-6/</guid>
      <description>A bunch of team members got the idea to hold trivia on a regular basis and created a webpage to manage the trivia app and play the game, but their API experience was limited and still needed to be built out. This is an application that uses APIs to control and manage a web app using existing data models.
The API in Flask to make the Trivia game functional was implemented.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Spain Electricity Shortfall Prediction</title>
      <link>https://keltings.github.io/post/project-3/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 11 Jun 2022 11:13:32 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://keltings.github.io/post/project-3/</guid>
      <description>The government of Spain is considering an expansion of it&amp;rsquo;s renewable energy resource infrastructure investments. As such, they require information on the trends and patterns of the countries renewable sources and fossil fuel energy generation.
This was a school project where I was tasked to build and deploy a regression model for the government of Spainto predict the shortfall between energy generated by fossil fuels and energy generated with renewable sources</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>South African Language Detection Analysis</title>
      <link>https://keltings.github.io/post/project-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 10 May 2022 11:00:59 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://keltings.github.io/post/project-2/</guid>
      <description>Language is an indispensable tool that can be used to deepen democracy and also contribute to the social, cultural, intellectual, economic and political life of the South African society. With such a multilingual population, it is only obvious that their systems and devices also communicate in multi-languages.
This was a kaggle competition in which I trained a classification model to predict in which South African language a piece of text is written in.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Server Deployment and Containerization</title>
      <link>https://keltings.github.io/post/project-8/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 12 Apr 2022 11:14:48 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://keltings.github.io/post/project-8/</guid>
      <description>The prime objective of this school project was to create a CI/CD pipeline, associate the pipeline&amp;rsquo;s one end to my Github repository, and connect the other end to the EKS cluster. I created the CI/CD pipeline programmatically using the code (Cloudformation template file) that the school provided. Link to Github Repository</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>About</title>
      <link>https://keltings.github.io/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://keltings.github.io/about/</guid>
      <description>I have a BSc Degree in Mathematics from the University of Nairobi. As a data-driven storyteller and customer-focused analyst, I use my skills in support of stakeholders when making decisions. I recently worked as a research assistant and an analyst in a project that used spatial data for network optimization.
I realized I had a passion for data analysis and could use my Math skills in the same field while working as a data officer in government institutes.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Contact</title>
      <link>https://keltings.github.io/contact/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://keltings.github.io/contact/</guid>
      <description>Follow me on this social media platforms:
Platform URL LinkedIn: linda-kelida GitHub: Keltings Twitter: lindahkelida Facebook: keltings Instagram: keltings Email: lkelida@gmail.com Phone: +254701922528 </description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
